[Music] today on the channel we're
going to make mted mini egg ice cream
which is something I had from an ice
cream store in Calgary last year and
this year it's a goate to flavor super
easy to make let's go and make [Music]
it yeah May by Markus have this flavor
every year I think or it's really quite
basic an ice cream it's a molted ice
cream base with mini egg pieces in it
but it's delicious so let's just get on and
make it what are you going to need you are
going to need 546 G of milk 616 G of whipping
cream 170 g of sugar 60 G of dextr 67 G of skim
milk powder 2 GS of tarum 4 G of L thin and
finally 50 g of dry malt extract we're going
to heat the space up we're going to use tarum as
our stabilizer that's a huge amount of tara gum
we are also going to add lein and emulsifier
because it just creates a creamier base cuz
there's not a huge amount of Flav elements in this
we want this to be super smooth so we're making
a 1500 G batch so that's two ninja creamy deluxe
three standard ninja creamies full three potential
churns and smaller churn machines whatever,
1500 G batch we're going to need 564 gr of
milk into that we are going
to add 66 G of whipping
cream Like That 160 g of
sugar it's 170 g of sugar
and on top of that we are going to add some
dextrose we're going to add in our stabilizer
we're going to need 60 G of dextrose we might as
well add in our milk powder at the same time which
is 67 G it may or may not go in there getting
our mini whisk we've got our tiny scales we're
going to add 2 G of tarum like that doesn't sound
like a lot but it is and into that we're going
to add 4 G of Lin like so you don't need to use
lein if you don't want to you don't need to use
a stabilizer if you don't want to that is your
choice into that mixture like that get all of
that out there stir this together this helps you
break up any remaining lumps also distribute the
stabilizer and aosif into the sugars helps
it dissolve like so that's going into there
start stirring this together we have one final
ingredient and that is our dry malt extract
and we are going to use 50 g of this this is
super dry powder goes everywhere there we go
this is dry malt extract this is a medium
concentration so if you're into beer making
ler making you'll know where to get that if you're
not into making that kind of thing go to a beer
making shop or wine making shop look on Amazon you
can buy this stuff everywhere you can get liquid
maltt extract there are some excellent liquid M
extracts um back in the UK they are essentially
this but with a very small amount of liquid added
to it it's heated up to make sure it's completely
dissolved and then that's your suspension maltt is
just a type of sugar um interesting fact back in
like the 40s 50s and 60s maltt was considered
a healthy sugar I mean it still is to be fair
because the way that your body processes mol
is much much faster easier and quicker than
you know table sugar um but there's no one on
earth that's going to say this sugar is good
for you we're going to put in our dry malt
powder slowly as it's a thin powder it goes
everywhere if you use Liquid maltt extract then
still use 50 g of it you're just adding a tiny
tiny bit of water into the base it won't make a
lot of difference uh interestingly enough maltt
powder is basically made up it's a natural
sugar from hops and barley um it's made up
of fructose glucose sucrose maltose something
else um all these different types of sugar are
naturally found in lots of ingredients
so these people that are my God I hate
fructose you you you you'll sit there and
eat a tablespoon of honey which is like 50%
learn a bit more about stuff anyway this
is all combined now we need to get this
on the heat tarum needs to come up to 85 CRA
185f and we need to leave it there for about
5 minutes that will help to dissolve this
dry M extract and we can go on from there I
broke my other tripod when I was camping in
the mountains so until I got a new one I'm
not going to film that I'm going to come back
once it's up I mean it's pretty straightforward
85c 185f for 5 minutes keep it there and then
you'll be good to go see you in a minute there
we go that's it 85z 185f kept it there for 5
minutes that's it I can still see like one or
two little lumps of that sunflower lesser thin
so I will strain that out before we CH it that
is it where's the lid that is now going to go in
the refrigerator um until tomorrow I want that
malt flavor to come through as much as possible so
you know what time is it now it's like 1:00 in the
afternoon so it's going to be probably 24 hours
in the fridge once we've done that we'll come back
and churn it and get this ice cream finished so
after the ice cream base is completely ched down
you're going to take it out the fridge and just
give it a whisk together make sure it's all come
together nicely to a nice homogeneous mix and get
this poured into your ice cream machine and get
it churning there are two different types of mini
egg the micro eggs which are always on the left
and the normal size ones we're going to use the
micro mini eggs because of this size batch we're
going to use three packs of these and that allows
for me to eat the old one here or there as you can
see they're tiny that one's gone we're going to
do just break some of them up so there are some
smaller pieces as well as the whole micro eggs in
there and at the last stage of your churn you're
going to start to spoon these into your mix it
might look like there's a lot going in here but
trust me it's the perfect amount anyway once your
churn is done take it out and put it in your tubs
as normal and get it in the freezer to harden
off the next day I take it out and have a look
and it's got glorious smell lovely taupey kind
of color to it and it Scoops perfectly as you
can see beautifully balanced recipe into a bowl
look at that that just makes your mouth water I
know it does me anyway I can't wait to try this
one so let's get on and see what it tastes like
melted mini egg just to reiterate the ice cream
store in calary made by Marcus do this flavor
every year and it's always one that I I mean
I've had it a couple of times and then I never
end up getting it but it's it's a delicious
mustache twizzle it's a delicious flavor he's
got some great flavors but doing it home there's
something a bit more about it let's see how this
tastes that is delicious I'd say actually you
could even go a bit more with The Malt powder
the dry malt extract it's like a medium kind of
intensity flavor it would probably benefit from
a little bit more so I'm going to say double The
Malt extract p powder if you if you use Liquid
malt extract just double that the chemical
makeup of the chocolate micro eggs is perfect
for ice cream they don't go super hard they don't
break your teeth they just you can bite into them
straight away it's a perfect size addin to be fair
we've got a glorious kind of taupey color it's not
white it's not brown it's somewhere in between
it's gentle and the coloring used on the microw
starts to leech out into the ice cream as you can
see by the little spinny video the liquid starts
to dissolve the coloring on the outside shell
of those micro eggs and you get little pockets
of color which is also fun this is a great one to
make super easy doesn't have to be micro eggs use
Mini Eggs English mini eggs taste very different
to Canadian mini eggs I haven't had us mini eggs
but it's the chocolate in North America the amount
of cocoa solids and cocoa butter that they use
is very different to how English Chocolate is
made and that is why you find English Chocolate
is better than North American chocolate it's
part of the legality of what they can class
as chocolate their requirement for chocolate has
a lower fat level which means you don't get that
super luxurious kind of taste that you do back
in England Europe is kind of scattered regarding
chocolate Belgium is synonymous with luxury
chocolate Swiss chocolate is incredible as well
Austrian German all of that part of the world
make incredible chocolate there are they are
known for milk chocolate or anything how did I
get onto a chocolate subject it's totally up to
you what you use I use what I like but Mini Eggs
in ice cream is a great combination especially
these ones love this flavor do give this one
a try Autumn Fall kind of flavors malt really
brings out if you're a beer ale lger Drinker
you'll get touches of that because of The Malt
is used in the Brewing process as well so if you
have a a type of maltt flavor that you like then
use that powder in your ice cream you get the
dark light and medium kind of uh flavor notes I
I wouldn't use the light cuz it just doesn't have
enough flavor medium or dark if you're using the
liquid malt extract it's predominantly dark that
they're using that as it's a byproduct of another
Manufacturing process so so give this one a try
thanks very much for watching don't forget to
like And subscribe next week we're going to
do something different not ice cream so bye